<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hive on David W. Streever</title>
    <link>http://blog.streever.com/categories/hive/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hive on David W. Streever</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://blog.streever.com/categories/hive/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Filtering Compactions in Hive</title>
      <link>http://blog.streever.com/articles/filtering-compactions-in-hive/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.streever.com/articles/filtering-compactions-in-hive/</guid>
      <description>Compactions can be seen with the standard SQL:
SHOW COMPACTIONS;  But this method has a couple of problems:
 No Filtering Timestamps are hard to interpret  Until additional functionality is available for this built in function, we can do the following.
Add links to the Metastore DB tables and create custom views to review compaction details.
Build Out Metadata Elements CREATE DATABASE IF NOT EXISTS custom_sys; DROP TABLE IF EXISTS `custom_sys`.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running LLAP on Compute Only Nodes</title>
      <link>http://blog.streever.com/articles/running-llap-on-compute-only-nodes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.streever.com/articles/running-llap-on-compute-only-nodes/</guid>
      <description>To run LLAP and/or Hive jobs on Compute Only Nodes you need to override a Hive Configuration default setting. Otherwise, queries will fail a majority of the time.
The hive configuration value hive.merge.nway.joins is true by default. But in Ambari 2.7.3+ (HDP 3+), it overrides the default setting and configures this to false. When this is left at the default true, intermittent failures of queries will happen on compute only nodes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Hive JDBC Federation</title>
      <link>http://blog.streever.com/articles/the-power-of-hive-jdbc-federation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.streever.com/articles/the-power-of-hive-jdbc-federation/</guid>
      <description>Hive jdbc-federation is a powerful mechanism to include external sources in your hive ecosystem. Apache Software Foundation has excellent docs detailing this feature referred to as the JDBCStorageHandler .
Interesting points about this StorageHandler include:
 Securing Passwords - Protects passwords using a &amp;lsquo;jceks&amp;rsquo; file stored on &amp;lsquo;hdfs&amp;rsquo; Partitioning - Could be used as an alternate to SQOOP for importing data to Hive  More Hive Metadata! Hive Metadata, previously only available via WebHCat which has been removed, can be retrieved through hive&amp;rsquo;s sys database.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>