<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Authors | David W. Streever</title>
    <link>http://www.streever.com/authors/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://www.streever.com/authors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Authors</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2019</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://www.streever.com/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Authors</title>
      <link>http://www.streever.com/authors/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.streever.com/authors/dstreev/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.streever.com/authors/dstreev/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A veteran Big Data evangelist, David leads a team at Cloudera that helps customers leverage Big Data and Streaming Technologies in the most effective ways. Deeply technical with 30 years of application development, systems design, and operational experience across Finance, Manufacturing, Transportation and, Healthcare. David has worked with 300+ Cloudera / Legacy Hortonworks customers over the last six years, helping them solve tough technical challenges across the Cloudera platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working through challenges and feature requests from clients, David helps identify patterns/solutions then works with Product and Engineering teams to guide the strategic direction of Cloudera engineering efforts including our Hybrid Cloud initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As these platforms mature, techniques change and evolve, David works with strategic customers to help them understand ways to leverage those performance and feature enhancements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Migrating or upgrading from previous platform releases? Knowing what to look for can save you a lot of work. David has been helping / advising customers on the upgrade path to make this transitions as easy as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.streever.com/images/dstreev/2016-HDP-Certs.png&#34; alt=&#34;HDP Certifications&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
